Hey English learners, welcome to this A2
English listening practice video. I hope
you're doing great and that you're ready
to practice your listening with another
video. Today I want to talk about flashc
cards. Some people like flashcards, some
people don't like flashcards. Uh I
recently started using flashcards
at the beginning of this year. So not
that recently but this year I started
using flashcards and uh I want to talk a
little bit about this topic about flashc
cards and how they can help you as a
language learner. And I'm not saying
that flashc cards are right for
everyone. Uh some people uh do fine
without flashc cards and they succeed in
their language learning without using
flashcards. Um but uh some people can
benefit from them. So I'd like to talk
about that in today's video. And uh I
know that a lot of you want to improve
your pronunciation in English. And if
that's you, if you want to pronounce
things better and feel more comfortable
with your pronunciation,
please check out my pronunciation
seminars. You can sign up for those by
clicking on the link down below uh in
the description below this video. uh
these pronunciation seminars that I make
uh will really help you uh improve the
way that you say things, say words, say
phrases and sentences in English. So,
please check those out. Okay, let's talk
about flashcards. So, in the past, I
used flash cards. I used them a couple
times maybe uh when learning different
languages, but I never stuck with them.
Meaning, I never continued using them
over a long period of time. And I
honestly didn't really like them that
much. And uh it was for different
reasons. Uh, but I decided this year to
try using them again and I've been using
them in a specific way uh to help me
with my French. So, uh, I use them every
day. Actually, I try to uh do them once
a day and not miss a day. I've been
pretty good actually. I haven't missed a
day of doing my flash cards in a long
time actually. So, I've been doing well
uh with them. Uh I use Ani. Uh this is
probably the most famous flashcard app.
There are some other popular ones as
well. I haven't tried them, but Ani is
good. It uses an SRS, a spaced
repetition system. Uh, and the way this
works is that it shows you uh the words
you need to review at the right time,
uh, at the optimal time when you should
review them, uh, based on some different
things. Um, and so, uh, there are other
apps that also use this type of, uh,
spaced repetition, and I think they're
probably all pretty good. Uh, let me
talk about how I use flashcards. So, uh,
I use them right now, uh, to help me
practice my speaking, actually. So, I
put the English side on the front and
then I have to think of how to say that
English phrase in French. Okay? So, I
don't do it the opposite way. I don't
put the French side on the front uh and
then think of what it means in English.
I did that years ago. Um, but that's not
how I currently use flashcards. Uh, I
put the English side on the front and
then I have to say, uh, that phrase in
French. So, um, I, as I said, I put
usually put a full phrase on the front.
Uh, I don't, um, just put a single word.
Uh, I put a phrase that contains
a new word that I want to learn or a new
phrase that I want to learn, a grammar
structure. Uh, perhaps uh once in a
while I'll even include two new things
like two new words in one sentence or
one phrase. Um, and uh, the way that I
choose uh, what to um, use to make these
flashcards, like which words, which
phrases I want to learn. This comes from
my own speaking practice. when I'm
speaking and I try to say something but
I don't know how to say that word or
that phrase. Uh I create a flash card uh
from that word or phrase. Uh so I know
that when I review my flash cards, I'm
not just reviewing random words. I'm
reviewing words and phrases that are
useful for me because I tried to say
them and I couldn't. So I know that I'm
learning relevant words and phrases. And
so uh I'm filling in my gaps, the gaps
in my speech of things that I want to
say but I can't say. So, uh, I can do
that, um, based on my speaking practice
with myself because I speak to myself
almost every day. And uh I can also um
uh find words that I'm missing uh based
on uh what I try to say in my
conversations with my tutor because I
also speak to a French tutor. So I do
that and I review my flashcards once a
day. Uh, it usually doesn't take too
long. And some people like to make
flashc cards using pictures or sounds
like audio flashcards or other things.
This is too much work for me. To be
honest, I don't want to spend that much
time creating flashcards. So, I don't do
this. Uh, I just put the phrase in
English and then I need to um say that
in French when I review it. I'm not
using flashc cards yet for Greek. Uh, I
started Greek recently. Uh, and there
are, for me, the reason why I don't use
them yet for Greek is because there are
still way too many common words and
phrases that I still don't know. And I
don't really want to make flashc cards
out of these words and phrases because
I'm going to learn them naturally
through listening and reading. Uh, I
think that over time, over the next few
months, I'm going to learn all of these
really common words and phrases
naturally just from seeing them over and
over again. So, I don't think it's that
necessary for me. You can still use
flashcards uh in the early phases of
learning a language. There's nothing
wrong with that, but I kind of prefer to
do a lot of listening and reading. And
when I do that, I'm exposed to these
very common words and phrases and
structures over and over again. So, it
isn't that necessary to do some separate
activity like flashcards to learn uh
phrases and words like the word
interesting or something like I'm going
to see that word over and over again
when I read things, when I listen. So, I
probably don't need to uh make flashc
cards for those types of words. I just
need to do my daily listening and
reading practice. But later on, I will
most likely use flashcards for Greek
when I'm learning words and phrases that
are important for me, but maybe they
aren't so common, so I don't see them so
often. um then for me that's when I
think flashc cards are really handy or
really useful. So that's just my opinion
but that works for me. Uh they really
work for me. Flashcards work for me at
my level uh in French because I'm
learning less common words and I don't
need to review them that much, but I
just need to see them again uh before I
forget them or maybe a little after I
forget them and just trust uh the spaced
repetition
uh schedule uh how it decides uh to show
me the words when it decides to show
them to me. Uh this spaced repetition
uh shows you the card uh at the optimal
time. I think uh around the time that
you're probably going to forget that
word. Uh so this depends on the card. Uh
and uh in some apps you can change this
I think like maybe you just want to
review the same words every day. Uh I
don't change this. I just trust how Ani
decides to schedule my reviews. So, uh,
some people change that. I don't. I just
trust it. Uh, I think that, um, it's
good to review words, um, around the
time you will probably forget them or
even a little after you've already
forgotten them. I think it's really
powerful to forget
a word and then relearn it. Uh I already
talked about this uh previously when I
talked about relearning Greek. Uh when I
relearn these words that I had
previously forgotten,
they feel so much stronger in my brain
now. So, I think it's powerful to
relearn words that you uh have
forgotten. Um, this isn't a big deal.
It's not a horrible thing to forget
words or forget phrases. Uh, when you
relearn them, um, many times, uh, they
will, uh, become, uh, just more solid in
your brain. Okay. And you can use flashc
cards at any time throughout the day.
Uh, one great thing about flashcards is
that you can review them when you're
doing things uh or when you're waiting
in places and you have nothing to do.
When you're waiting in line, this is a
great time to do flashcards. when you're
on the bus, uh when uh you uh are doing
something that doesn't require your
attention and you can pull out your
flash cards uh for a few minutes and
review some cards, it's great. It's a
good way to um take advantage of those
times throughout the day when you're
just waiting and you can't do anything.
That's a good time to review flashcards.
I'll be honest, it's not the funnest
thing. Reviewing flashcards is not the
most interesting activity, but it has
helped me. I've seen uh the benefits of
using flashcards. I've been able to use
phrases that I learned from my
flashcards and I use them with my tutor
for the first time and it feels good to
use that phrase that I reviewed and
learned and I use it correctly. So, I've
seen the benefits and depending on
your personality,
your preferences,
what you like, and maybe um where you
are in your uh language learning
process, maybe flashcards could be
helpful for you. Um, maybe you can try
them out and see if you like them. So,
they're not for everyone, but I think
it's worth it to try them out and see if
they work for you. So, hopefully uh you
enjoyed this video and I hope uh this
was good advice and I know it was good
practice for your listening. Remember
that you can get my pronunciation
training in which I help you pronounce
things more like I do or other native
speakers do. So, if you want that
pronunciation training, click on the
link down below to sign up. All right.
Thank you all so much for watching this
video and I'll talk to you in the next